Oz DiGennaro

Boulder, CO

Email: oz@ozdigennaro.com

Mobile: 720.375.1364

ozdigennaro.com

<u>github.com/ozdigennaro</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/ozdigennaro</u>

Summary:

Web developer. Ruby on Rails. Full-stack. Products start to finish. TDD. DevOps - automated deployment using chef

Key Accomplishments:

Expert in Ruby on Rails

chef

Intensive use of PostgreSQL

Front-end: javascript, jQuery, HAML, CSS, HTML

Full-stack

Speed and memory optimization

Project tools: git, pivotaltracker, jira, jenkins, travis, github.

Relevant Experience:

Senior Developer at Oppenheimer Funds for Ciber: Implemented automated deployment using chef and vmWare (green field)

Senior Developer at Liaison International: Supported and enhances a complex rails app for higher education applications.

Senior Developer at Fluorofinder LLC: Developed and maintain a sophisticated bio-tech search engine on Ruby on Rails. Full-stack and db.

Founder and Senior Developer at Galgal Systems LLC: Developed a set of tools for enhanced ePub and enhanced UX for websites. Semantic web in the backroom. Rails app with Adobe SWF embedded (flash player).

Senior Contributor to the IVCC project: Project Manager and Semantic Contributor to the Mosquito and Malaria control project. Multiple web sites. Java team.

Job History:

Oppenheimer Funds contracting for Ciber, Denver **Senior Developer**

Sept.2014 to Feb.2015

Investor and Advisor websites. chef and vmWare vRA. Ruby on Rails, Oracle, HAML, JavaScript (with jQuery), rspec, mongodb, redis; tcserver, jRuby; heterogeneous distributed servers; agile, jira. These websites have extreme performance requirements as well as demands for reliability and security. www.oppenheimerfunds.com

Liaison International, Boson **Senior Developer** Aug.2013 to Sep.2014

Building the Centralized Application Service. Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Microsoft SQL, HAML, JavaScript (with jQuery), minitest; extensive ETL; agile, extensive pair programming, distributed team. The clients are students applying to professional schools (medical, dental, etc). www.liaison-intl.com

Fluorofinder LLC, Denver **Partner and Senior Developer** Jan.2012 to May.2013

Building a SaaS website for bio-high-tech: Flow Cytometry research. Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HAML, JavaScript (with jQuery), rspec, cucumber; rackspace, linux, nginx. The clients are bio-tech researchers and medical clinicians. Fluorofinder makes their life easier and their work more efficient by supporting complex search methods to build a good Cytometry experiment (set of reagents: anti-bodies and dyes). www.fluorofinder.com

Galgal Systems LLC, Boulder Founder and Senior Developer

May.2006 to Jan.2012 (overlaps with other development positions)

Building a startup company creating development tools for the Semantic Web. Market research, technology research, selection of implementation methods. Development of demo and prototype. Tools for enhanced eBooks and text-intensive web sites (Science / Technology / Medicine. Legal, eLearning), with semantically-informed server, including use of multiple semantic web services (OpenCalais, dbpedia). Adobe Flex, Rails framework to deliver SWF; Apache, Python, linux, PostgreSQL. Drupal. www.galgalsystems.com

Volkscast LLC, New York city Senior Developer

April.2010 to October.2010

Building technology to create a net appliance for high-definition video acquisition. Select and implement a very-small single board linux box with the computation and bandwidth to support HD video, streaming to the net to a server using Wowza. Distribution using Adobe OSMF (Open Source Media Framework). Linux, gtreaming, Amazon EC2 servers. Client and Server. www.linkedin.com/company/volkscast-corp

CSU Infectious Disease Annex, Fort Collins, CO Innovative Vector Control Consortium Senior consultant

December.2008 to May.2009

Malaria Decision Support System for third-world countries (Africa and Mexico). duties: Semantic expert on the project, with attention to OB-Ontology and malaria ontologies. Project manager. Complex set of websites with complex database. Extra attention to the geodata requirements of the project. http://www.ivcc.com/projects/mdss.htm

Cognitive Solutions, Inc., Golden, CO Senior Developer – printing embedded system

December.2005 to September.2006

Specified and developed **PCL5 interpreter** for addition to an existing set of printer software and hardware, reviewed market requirements, planned and executed the integration of the PCL5 interpreter, with previous Cognitive printers, worked closely with the engineers at Cognitive during the process. Specified test plan for PCL5 compatibility. Fast performance was a significant requirement, to meet competitive offerings. C and C++ on ARM using Eclipse-based tools. http://www.cognitive.com/

SkeyTek Inc., Boulder Engineering Management, Project Management March.2004 to December.2005

Team leadership of a Linux-based **RFID Reader** network, including web servers, web services, Service Oriented Architecture. RFID readers and stand-alone units. Managed a quarter-million dollar project from start to finish, resulting in the delivery of a product: SkyeTek's first consumer hand-held reader. Started design of portable and extensible ReaderWare to migrate SkyeTek's center of competence from hardware to embedded software. Implemented extensive changes in engineering development methodology, process, and documentation. Created process for engineering review and release of product documentation and manufacturing packages, bug log. http://www.skyetek.com/

Education:

University of California at San Diego, CA

Candidate in Philosophy in German Literature

University in Erlangen, Germany

Germanistik

Deutsche Academische Austausch Dienst Fellow

Technical University in Berlin, Germany

Germanistik

University of California at San Diego, CA

Regents Fellow

University of Illinois, Champaign, IL

Bachelor of Arts in Chemistry with Math and Physics Graduation with distinction

Publishing and Speaking:

- Meetup organizer and chief speaker at the Boulder Semantic Web meetup 2008-2012.
- Semantic presentation to UCAR.
- Many conference speeches about Printers, Image Processing.

Interests: bike riding, hiking, ham radio, coastal cruising.